



V. RAYADURAI

Cloud Specialist / Storage / Backup Administrator INDIA | + 91 9840204223

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

9 + years of experience with AWS/Microsoft Azure/Enterprise Storage/Backup Specialist in IT Infrastructure based on 24X7 support environment. Possessing a strong expertise in operational, migration and implementation support of AWS, AZURE Computing Technologies, EMC VNX, Hitachi, IBM,HP storage, EMC Networker, HP Data protector. Deep experience with AWS and AZURE components such as EC2, S3, RDS, Auto scaling, ELB,VPC, Storage Gateway,Glacier,Route 53, DMS,SMS, CloudWatch, SNS, Direct connect,VNET,VPN, Blob etc. Having very good Experience in Storage provisioning and troubleshooting of EMC, Hitachi,IBM, HP Storage Array and Backup EMC Networker, HP Data protector and Symantec Netbackup.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud - AWS Certified Solutions Architect

AZURE Cloud - Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

❖ MSc - Recognized by Bharathidasan University 2002 − 2004 (73%)

❖ BSc - Recognized by Bharathidasan University 1999 − 2002 (61%)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems :: Windows, LINUX & UNIX

Cloud :: AWS Cloud & Microsoft Azure Cloud

Storage Arrays :: EMC –VMAX series, VNX, CLARiiON , Hitachi VSP,HP EVA, Sun Storage TEK, IBM XIV

Backup :: HP Data Protector, EMC Networker, Symantec Netbackup

Tape Library :: HP MSL 6000, 4048 & IBM TS3200

SAN Switch :: Brocade & Cisco

Network Switch :: HP PoE switch

Monitoring Tool :: Science logic, Sapphire, eG Innovations and I-enable

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cloud Specialist / Storage / Backup Administrator 3i -infotech Limited

July 2016 to Till Chennai

- Worked on Amazon Web Services and Microsoft AZURE (EC2, ELB, VPC, S3, IAM, RDS, Route 53, CloudWatch, SNS,EFS, Glacier,Storage Gateway,Direct Connect,DMS,SMS,Cloud trail,App services,VNET,Blob storage,Disk Storage).
- Provide end-to-end customer support and responsible to lead Cloud, Storage, Backup, Database and Application

- Design, testing and implementation of Cloud based system architectures
- Planning and deploying AWS and AZURE environment
- Assess and evaluate on-premise systems for migration.
- Estimating AWS and Azure usage costs and identifying operational cost control mechanisms
- Implemented a structured design process for creating a hybrid cloud architectures
- Install and configure virtual cloud instances
- Migrating physical infrastructure with application in the AWS and AZURE cloud
- Cloud Data Migrations -20 Migrating an existing on-premises application and Database to AWS and AZURE through CloudEndure and RiverMeadow tool
- Experience in setting up cluster environment for load balancing and high availability
- Configured and installed Oracle, MS SQL, Mysql, PostgreSQL databases in AWS and AZURE.
- Configured Database Replication.
- Code-level application security (IAM roles, credentials, encryption, etc.)
- Creating Customer Managed Policies, AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM)
- Participated in networking for VLAN infrastructure for cloud customers
- Establish Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) to customer environments
- VNET system routes and underlying route table that Local VNet Rules.
- Installed and Setup Web Servers (Apache and Tomcat), DB Server (MySQL).
- Setup/Managing VPC, Subnets; make connection between different zones
- Create/Managing buckets on S3 (CLI) and store db and logs backup
- Development of PowerShell command scripts for automating client/server functions
- Created Alerts and configured monitoring of specified metrics to manage their cloud infrastructure
- Storage Provisioning on VMAX, VNX, Clariion , IBM XIV , HP EVA and NVR using zoning, LUN masking
- Experience with monitoring tools such as CloudWatch, Science logic, Sapphire
- Good understanding of ELB, security groups, NACL, NAT, firewall and Route 53.
- Day to day provisioning of storage (Storage device selection/creation, Zoning, LUN Masking).
- Storage Provisioning on VMAX, VNX, Hitachi, IBM, HP using zoning, LUN masking, mapping
- Backup using EMC Networker, HP Data Protector and Symantec Netbackup
- Local replication using Snapshot and Snapview.
- Remote replication using Mirrorview and SAN copy

Cloud / Storage Administrator TRELCO Security System

Jan 2016 to July 2016 DOHA- QATAR

- Worked on Amazon Web Services (EC2, ELB, VPC, S3, IAM, RDS, Route 53, CloudWatch, SNS,).
- Installed and Setup Web Servers (Apache and Tomcat), DB Server (MySQL).
- Setup/Managing VPC, Subnets; make connection between different zones; Blocking suspicious ip/subnet via ACL
- Create/Managing buckets on S3 (CLI) and store db and logs backup
- Support cloud servers including security configurations, patching, and troubleshooting.
- Responsible for supporting AL-Ahli Bank Branch offices and Partner Countries (Server, Storage, Backups, Network)
- Managed and deployed LUNS from EMC, IBM, HP storage frames to multiple servers using the Navisphere and Unisphere manager.
- Storage Provisioning on VMAX, VNX, Clariion, IBM XIV, HP EVA and NVR using zoning, LUN masking
- Backup using HP Data Protector and Symantec Netbackup

- AWS Services (EC2, EBS, S3, RDS, AMI, ELB, IAM, VPC, ROUTE53, EFS, CLOUDWATCH, SNS)
- Configure Security Group and VPC PEERING connection
- AWS VPN Connection and AWS direct connection
- Configure Security Group and VPC PEERING connection
- Create/Managing buckets on S3 (CLI) and store db and logs backup
- Implemented high availability with Azure Classic and Azure Resource Manager deployment models.
- Proficient in dealing with Windows Azure Compute, Networking, Storage, Security, Identity, Developer Services, Monitoring and Management.
- Expertise in Virtual Networks, Virtual Machines, Cloud Services, Express Route, Traffic Manager, VPN, Load Balancing, Auto Scaling.
- Configuring zoning and monitoring BROCADE Switch.
- Create RAID Groups, Bind LUNs, and Create Storage Groups using
- Involved in day to day Storage Provisioning on Sun Storage Tek using zoning, LUN masking, mapping and reclamation.
- Configuring zoning and monitoring BROCADE Switch.
- Managed work requests & coordinating implementation of projects.
- Creating RAID Groups, binding LUN's, Creating Meta LUN's, Creating Storage Groups, AccessLogix and registering hosts as per customer Requirements.
- Alias and Zoning on SAN Switches
- SAN storage allocations/de-allocations
- Configuration and troubleshooting for the storage issues on various host environments

Storage / Backup Administrator

Jan 2012 to March 2015

Hewlett Packard (Outsourced through Saggezza India PVT Ltd)

Chennai

- Hands on experience in providing EMC VNX ,Clariion, sand EVA
- Backup using EMC Networker and HP Data protector
- Maintain proper Backup schedule, Daily usage and performance of storage
- Configuring ZONES on Brocade switch to provide security in Storage Area Network
- Create RAID Groups, Bind LUNs, and Create Storage Groups using
- Troubleshooting, monitoring and reporting on the SAN Environment
- Analyzing the Logs and performance issues, Expanding DP pools
- Adding new host to storage environment.
- Strong knowledge of Data Center, Backup, Tape libraries
- Maintaining HP inventory for ISO 27001 Data center.

Storage / Backup Administrator

Jan 2008 to Jan 2012

Hewlett Packard (Outsourced through ALCHEMIST HR Services PVT Ltd) **Chennai**

Chemai

- Hands on experience in providing EMC VNX ,Clariion, EVA, HP DP
- Create RAID groups and LUN
- Data Center Infra Structure Management
- Performing day to day activities like monitoring, backups, health checkups, access permissions, server related issues/requests based on will solve the issues.
- Backup schedules, rotation schedules, and a retention scheme
- Managing, monitoring and raising tickets with ALCMS.
- Performing backups and media management.. MSL 6000 & MSL 4048 Tape Libraries.

E-mail: rayadurai@gmail.com, Phone: INDIA +91 9840204223

- Maintaining HP inventory for ISO 27001 Data center.
- Conducted preventative maintenance inspections.
- Managing, monitoring and raising tickets with ALCMS.
- Performing backups and media management.. MSL 6000 & MSL 4048 Tape Libraries.
- Maintaining HP inventory for ISO 27001 Data center.

Quality Analyst KVR Enterprises Jan 2008 to Jan 2012 Chennai

- Analysis of water samples & Provide feedback after error analysis of samples audited.
- Handling a team of 50 members & Provide the required reporting

PERSONAL PROFILE:

Name : Rayadurai. V

Languages Known : English, Tamil.

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that all above information are true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Chennai Rayadurai. V